<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>http://graphitefriction.com/</id>
  <title>Graphite Friction</title>
  <author>
    <name>Sarah White</name>
  </author>
  <updated>2012-07-05T13:30:00Z</updated>
  <link href="http://graphitefriction.com/feed.atom" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="http://graphitefriction.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <entry>
    <id>http://graphitefriction.com/blog/2012/07/05/chronicling-the-fedora-community-area-in-millimeters-and-pixels/</id>
    <title>Chronicling the Fedora Community Area in Millimeters and Pixels</title>
    <updated>2012-07-05T13:30:00Z</updated>
    <published>2012-07-05T13:30:00Z</published>
    <link href="http://graphitefriction.com/blog/2012/07/05/chronicling-the-fedora-community-area-in-millimeters-and-pixels/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <author>
      <name>Sarah White</name>
    </author>
    <category scheme="http://graphitefriction.com/blog/tags" term="fedora" />
    <category scheme="http://graphitefriction.com/blog/tags" term="event" />
    <summary>
      Representing Fedora at the Summit sounded great when I was safely ensconced in my office, chatting on IRC, weeks before the event.  But once I approached the booth at the Hynes Convention Center, a horde of heebie-jeebies streaked down my spine screaming, Run away! Run away!.
Face to face, live action conversation? It can&#8217;t be paused, reconsidered or erased. Answering direct questions without the luxury of composing my thoughts on paper? Why, oh why hasn&#8217;t anyone invented a delete key for my mouth!
During the first full day of booth activities, I retreated behind my cameras to document the constant activity...
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      &lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;Representing &lt;a href=&quot;http://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Red_Hat_Summit_2012&quot;&gt;Fedora at the Summit&lt;/a&gt; sounded great when I was safely ensconced in my office, chatting on &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;IRC&lt;/span&gt;, weeks before the event.  But once I approached the booth at the Hynes Convention Center, a horde of heebie-jeebies streaked down my spine screaming, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Run away! Run away!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Face to face, live action conversation? It can&amp;#8217;t be paused, reconsidered or erased. Answering direct questions without the luxury of composing my thoughts on paper? Why, oh why hasn&amp;#8217;t anyone invented a delete key for my mouth!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the first full day of booth activities, I retreated behind my cameras to document the constant activity in the Fedora Community area. I photographed attendees visiting the Fedora booth, hanging with Beefy Miracle, and enjoying the mid-afternoon hot dog snack hour. All of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/graphitefriction/&quot;&gt;photographs I took during the Summit&lt;/a&gt; are posted on my Flickr stream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/images/fedorasummit2012/fedora_booth_friends.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/images/fedorasummit2012/beefymiracle_mustard.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also recorded two talks presented in the Fedora Community area: Ryan O&amp;#8217;Hara&amp;#8217;s &lt;em&gt;Network Load Balancing for the 21st Century With Keepalived and HAProxy&lt;/em&gt; and Dan Allen&amp;#8217;s &lt;em&gt;JBoss AS7 on Fedora&lt;/em&gt; as well as the server and system installation for the next day&amp;#8217;s Fedora &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;ARM&lt;/span&gt; demonstration. Once I finish processing the videos, I&amp;#8217;ll post them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/images/fedorasummit2012/ryanohara_loadbalance.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Ryan O&amp;#39;Hara&quot; alt=&quot;Ryan O&amp;#39;Hara&quot; /&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/images/fedorasummit2012/danallen_as7onfedora.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Dan Allen&quot; alt=&quot;Dan Allen&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/images/fedorasummit2012/jonmasters_arm_demo.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Jon Masters&quot; alt=&quot;Jon Masters&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, after Jon Masters&amp;#8217; crowd-gathering &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;ARM&lt;/span&gt; demonstration, I forced myself to stow the cameras. I took position behind the booth, no camera lenses or laptop to filter my I/O. The gaps in my knowledge soon became apparent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left:2em;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No, I&amp;#8217;m not familiar with the wide variety of acronyms applied to the hardware in the one laptop per per child computer or what version of Fedora it is running.&lt;/strong&gt; Luke Macken saved the attendee from my panicky stare, and now I know it&amp;#8217;s an &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;ARM&lt;/span&gt; processor, running Sugar on a Stick, and the newest laptop has a much better keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left:2em;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t know what version of Apache httpd is packaged in Fedora 17.&lt;/strong&gt; Tom Callaway fired up a terminal and found the information. &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.fedoraproject.org/packages/httpd&quot;&gt;2.2.22&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the most popular question at the booth:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left:2em;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did Beefy Miracle come to be named Beefy Miracle?&lt;/strong&gt; After numerous attempts, I realized I couldn&amp;#8217;t succinctly explain the &lt;a href=&quot;http://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Guidelines_for_release_names&quot;&gt;Fedora release naming process steps&lt;/a&gt; in the correct order. Ruth Suehle, Sandro Mathys and Tom had to save people from my disordered explanations numerous times. They can iterate the naming process without blinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I did answer questions regarding one of the new items at the booth, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://fedoraproject.org/wiki/JBossAS7&quot;&gt;AS 7 on Fedora 17&lt;/a&gt; flyer.  I can recite the commands to install the AS 7 package, start, stop and deploy it, what is and isn&amp;#8217;t currently in the packaged profile, what&amp;#8217;s on deck to be in updated releases, and where to find help and participate with AS 7 and future packaging goals.  I was stumped though when asked about the differences between Fedora and AS 7 versus another distribution and Websphere.  I need to brush up on the features of other application servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m not a well-rounded Fedora representative yet, but manning the booth was a huge kickstart. I learned the answers to tons of questions from the other Fedora representatives and discovered the concerns of potential and current Fedora users. The best thing about volunteering at the booth was meeting so many great people: the conference attendees who visited the booth and the Fedora advocates I had previously only chatted with on &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;IRC&lt;/span&gt;. I can&amp;#8217;t thank everyone enough times for answering my questions or for sorting through my jumbled explanations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, there are two questions I can confidently respond to now without pause or consideration because Ruth wrote down the answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yes, it is a Raspberry Pi. No, you can&amp;#8217;t have it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/images/fedorasummit2012/raspberrypi_fedora17.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you&amp;#8217;d like a specific picture from the Fedora booth in its high-resolution, mega-size version (some are available in large format &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;JPG&lt;/span&gt; and some in &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;RAW&lt;/span&gt;), just shoot me a message.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://graphitefriction.com/blog/2012/06/16/molecules-and-predators-and-arquillian/</id>
    <title>Molecules and Predators and Arquillian</title>
    <updated>2012-06-16T13:30:00Z</updated>
    <published>2012-06-16T13:30:00Z</published>
    <link href="http://graphitefriction.com/blog/2012/06/16/molecules-and-predators-and-arquillian/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <author>
      <name>Sarah White</name>
    </author>
    <category scheme="http://graphitefriction.com/blog/tags" term="arquillian" />
    <category scheme="http://graphitefriction.com/blog/tags" term="design" />
    <summary>
      During the past year Arquillian has matured from a testing harness to a testing platform as it integrates with Selenium, Graphene, Spring, Android and more. In parallel, the Arquillain contributors have channeled their interlanguage and interframework development exploits into an ongoing tale of intergalactic bug extermination. Ike is gathering a crew as he expands into new frontiers. He&#8217;s using new tools to hunt for bugs and congifuring weapons with super strong materials to eliminate the bugs.
          Crafting the look and feel of Ike, his crew, and their gear has this sci-fic fangirl constantly plotting ways to beam (forgive me, Scotty) the...
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      &lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;During the past year &lt;a href=&quot;http://arquillian.org/&quot;&gt;Arquillian&lt;/a&gt; has matured from a testing harness to a testing platform as it integrates with Selenium, Graphene, Spring, Android and more. In parallel, the Arquillain contributors have channeled their interlanguage and interframework development exploits into an ongoing tale of intergalactic bug extermination. Ike is gathering a crew as he expands into new frontiers. He&amp;#8217;s using new tools to hunt for bugs and congifuring weapons with super strong materials to eliminate the bugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crafting the look and feel of Ike, his crew, and their gear has this sci-fic fangirl constantly plotting ways to beam (forgive me, Scotty) the Arquillan platform artwork to the next dimension. However, the platform has diversified so rapidly that I can&amp;#8217;t pull off diagrams, icons, and logos during all-night design binges hours before a presentation deadline. Nor does such a draw-and-dash design frenzy do the indvidual extensions, adaptors, and modules the creative and finely polished rendering justice they deserve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m also a bit of a monster after thirty-six hours of no sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, Arquillian now has a &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/arquillian/arquillian-artwork&quot;&gt;seperate repository&lt;/a&gt; where graphics can be conceptualized, drafted, and finalized over multiple iterations. It&amp;#8217;s powered by community requests, community contributions, and community feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Initial logo concepts: Graphene and Arquillian Spring Framework extension&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past two weeks I&amp;#8217;ve been sketching logo ideas for Graphene and the Arquillian Spring Framework extension.  I selected the sketches I think have potential and uploaded them for the feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://arquillian.org/modules/graphene-extension/&quot;&gt;Graphene&lt;/a&gt; is designed to enhancement a Selenium project by focusing on rapid development and usability in the Java environment.  Graphene takes its name from the semiconducting material composed of a single layer of carbon atoms arranged into a 2D honeycomb lattice. Graphene is one of the strongest materials in existence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to admit, I don&amp;#8217;t feel that pencil sketches were great at coveying some of my ideas. Mainly because I realized I really suck at drawing hexagrams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/images/graphene/graphenehexagrams.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/images/graphene/abstracthexagram.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/images/graphene/grapheneshield.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next three concepts required lots of hexagrams, so I stopped torturing my eraser and fired up Inkscape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/images/graphene/grid1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/images/graphene/grid2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/images/graphene/grid3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://arquillian.org/modules/spring-extension/&quot;&gt;Spring extension&lt;/a&gt; is &lt;a href=&quot;https://community.jboss.org/thread/197356&quot;&gt;Jakob Narloch&amp;#8217;s Google Summer of Code project&lt;/a&gt;. It injects Spring beans into test cases and supports Spring annotations. Jakob asked for a simple logo, but my disciple went &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;AWOL&lt;/span&gt; and I ended up sketching a few, detailed ideas after word webbing like the vocabulary nerd I am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/images/spring/springs.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/images/spring/bow.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/images/spring/viper.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/images/spring/foxspring.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/images/spring/mutanttrap.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://graphitefriction.com/blog/2012/06/15/fatal-error-problematic-frame-there-goes-my-core/</id>
    <title>A Fatal Error. A Problematic Frame. There Goes My Core.</title>
    <updated>2012-06-15T13:30:00Z</updated>
    <published>2012-06-15T13:30:00Z</published>
    <link href="http://graphitefriction.com/blog/2012/06/15/fatal-error-problematic-frame-there-goes-my-core/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <author>
      <name>Sarah White</name>
    </author>
    <category scheme="http://graphitefriction.com/blog/tags" term="java" />
    <category scheme="http://graphitefriction.com/blog/tags" term="ruby" />
    <category scheme="http://graphitefriction.com/blog/tags" term="smack" />
    <summary>
      A fatal error has been detected by the Java Runtime Environment:
SIGSEGV (0xb) at pc=0x00007f995359f24d, pid=4003, tid=140296504968960
Translation for mere humans: It&#8217;s dead, Sarah. You killed something important-sounding by attempting to build a teeny, tiny little webpage on localhost. Sigh.
Java VM: OpenJDK 64-Bit Server VM (22.0-b10 mixed mode linux-amd64 compressed oops)
Is this an oops my laptop accidentally mixed up some important bits? Or OOPS the official operations processing specialists ARE FROWNING UPON my coding attempts?
Problematic frame:
C  [libjruby-cext.so+0x2624d] Java_org_jruby_cext_Native_freeHandle+0xb7
Oh, so now it&#8217;s just &#8216;problematic&#8217; not FATAL. Make up your mind already!
Failed to write core dump. Core dumps have been disabled. To enable...
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;A fatal error has been detected by the Java Runtime Environment:&amp;#x000A;SIGSEGV (0xb) at pc=0x00007f995359f24d, pid=4003, tid=140296504968960&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Translation for mere humans: It&amp;#8217;s dead, Sarah. You killed something important-sounding by attempting to build a teeny, tiny little webpage on localhost. &lt;em&gt;Sigh.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Java VM: OpenJDK 64-Bit Server VM (22.0-b10 mixed mode linux-amd64 compressed oops)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this an &lt;em&gt;oops&lt;/em&gt; my laptop accidentally mixed up some important bits? Or &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;OOPS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; the official operations processing specialists &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;ARE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;FROWNING&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;UPON&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; my coding attempts?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Problematic frame:&amp;#x000A;C  [libjruby-cext.so+0x2624d] Java_org_jruby_cext_Native_freeHandle+0xb7&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, so now it&amp;#8217;s just &amp;#8216;problematic&amp;#8217; not &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;FATAL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Make up your mind already!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Failed to write core dump. Core dumps have been disabled. To enable core dumping, try &quot;ulimit -c unlimited&quot; before starting Java again.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Core dumps sound bad. They&amp;#8217;re always the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;LAST&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;RESORT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in movies.  If we detach the rest of the train cars maybe we&amp;#8217;ll make the leap across the giant canyon. If we shoot our nuclear reactor out a torpedo tube maybe we&amp;#8217;ll kill the bad guys chasing us (but obliterate all life in the Pacific ocean).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Aborted (core dumped)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The heck with the stupid core anyway. Where&amp;#8217;s my dilithium crystal virtual machine? Then I could sling shot my laptop around the sun before the terminal would even dare to mention errors to me. Of course, then my laptop would probably learn to cloak itself as well and hide from me.  My laptop might not be able to pass the Turing test but I betcha it could score major points on the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;DSM&lt;/span&gt;-IV antisocial personality test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I don&amp;#8217;t want to hear anything about how one&amp;#8217;s computer is a reflection of its user.&lt;/p&gt;
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
