<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>http://graphitefriction.com/</id>
  <title>Graphite Friction</title>
  <author>
    <name>Sarah White</name>
  </author>
  <updated>2012-10-09T13:30:00Z</updated>
  <link href="http://graphitefriction.com/feed.atom" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="http://graphitefriction.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <entry>
    <id>http://graphitefriction.com/blog/2012/10/09/is-that-fedora-running-on-a-raspberry-pi/</id>
    <title>Is that Fedora running on a Raspberry Pi?</title>
    <updated>2012-10-09T13:30:00Z</updated>
    <published>2012-10-09T13:30:00Z</published>
    <link href="http://graphitefriction.com/blog/2012/10/09/is-that-fedora-running-on-a-raspberry-pi/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <author>
      <name>Sarah White</name>
    </author>
    <category scheme="http://graphitefriction.com/blog/tags" term="raspberry-pi" />
    <category scheme="http://graphitefriction.com/blog/tags" term="fedora" />
    <category scheme="http://graphitefriction.com/blog/tags" term="event" />
    <summary>
      by Sarah White and Dan Allen
      &#8220;Why, yes it is! To be exact, it&#8217;s a Fedora Remix running on a Raspberry Pi.&quot;
      That was a popular exchange at the Fedora booth during this year&#8217;s Ohio LinuxFest. The iconic Model B Raspberry Pi, running Fedora Remix and proudly displaying the Beefy Miracle fireworks on a XFCE desktop, was drawing lots of attention.
      
      As OLF attendees quickly discovered, using the desktop requires a little extra patience since the libraries aren&#8217;t (yet) optimized for the hardware. But, don&#8217;t underestimate this board. It packs a powerful punch and future releases plan to take full advantage of its...
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      &lt;h4 style=&quot;margin-top: -1em;&quot;&gt;by Sarah White and &lt;a href=&quot;http://google.com/profiles/dan.j.allen&quot;&gt;Dan Allen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;#8220;Why, yes it is!&lt;/strong&gt; To be exact, it&amp;#8217;s a Fedora &lt;em&gt;Remix&lt;/em&gt; running on a Raspberry Pi.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;That was a popular exchange at the Fedora booth during this year&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://ohiolinux.org&quot;&gt;Ohio LinuxFest&lt;/a&gt;. The iconic Model B Raspberry Pi, running Fedora Remix and proudly displaying the Beefy Miracle fireworks on a &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;XFCE&lt;/span&gt; desktop, was drawing lots of attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/images/raspberry_pi/xfce_desktop.jpg&quot; title=&quot;XFCE Desktop on the Raspberry Pi Fedora Remix&quot; alt=&quot;XFCE Desktop on the Raspberry Pi Fedora Remix&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;OLF&lt;/span&gt; attendees quickly discovered, using the desktop requires a little extra patience since the libraries aren&amp;#8217;t (yet) optimized for the hardware. But, don&amp;#8217;t underestimate this board. It packs a powerful punch and future releases plan to take full advantage of its capabilities to speed up execution of the programs. (See &lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.fedoraproject.org/pipermail/arm/2012-July/003669.html&quot;&gt;this fedora-arm mailinglist post&lt;/a&gt; or search for &amp;#8220;soft-float vs hard-float&amp;#8221; for details)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questions at the booth that followed were typically:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&amp;#8220;Who maintains it?&amp;#8221;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&amp;#8220;Where do I get it?&amp;#8221;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&amp;#8220;How do I install it?&amp;#8221;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, let&amp;#8217;s start with, &amp;#8220;What &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;is&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; a Raspberry Pi?&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What is a Raspberry Pi?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Raspberry Pi is a system-on-a-chip (SoC) single-board computer. In other words, it&amp;#8217;s an incredibly compact general purpose computer. It even fits inside one of my mini pie dishes. &lt;em&gt;Mmmm&lt;/em&gt;, pie!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/images/raspberry_pi/pi_in_a_pie.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Raspberry Pi as a Pie&quot; alt=&quot;Raspberry Pi as a Pie&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#8217;s back up and begin with the central component that makes this all possible, the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;ARM&lt;/span&gt; chip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ARM_architecture&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;ARM&lt;/span&gt; chips&lt;/a&gt; are the most widely-produced processors in the world because they are small, cheap and require minimal power. They are found in smart phones, tablets, routers, embedded controllers, gaming consoles and streaming digital media devices. As the chips become more powerful and SoCs less expensive, consumer operating systems such as Fedora can be installed on them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several companies manufacture and sell &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;ARM&lt;/span&gt;-based SoC computers that cost under $100 that are specifically designed for you to install your Linux distribution of choice. The Raspberry Pi is notable for its $35 price tag, less than half the price of the next cheapest &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;ARM&lt;/span&gt;-based SoC, the $89 BeagleBone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Raspberry Pi Model B is based on the Broadcom BCM2835 SoC and includes these components and ports:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;ARM1176JZF-S 700 MHz processor (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.arm.com/products/processors/classic/arm11&quot;&gt;ARM11 family&lt;/a&gt;, armv6 architecture)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;VideoCore IV &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;GPU&lt;/span&gt;, OpenGL ES 2.0, 1080p30 h.264/&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;MPEG&lt;/span&gt;-4 &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;AVC&lt;/span&gt; high-profile decoder&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;256 Megabytes of &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;RAM&lt;/span&gt; (shared between the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;CPU&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;GPU&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Two &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;USB&lt;/span&gt; 2.0 ports&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;10/100 Ethernet (RJ45) controller&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;HDMI&lt;/span&gt; and composite &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;RCA&lt;/span&gt; video outputs&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;HDMI&lt;/span&gt; and 3.5mm jack audio outputs&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;MicroSD card slot&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;GPIO&lt;/span&gt; pins&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;5V Micro &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;USB&lt;/span&gt; power jack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s how the parts are laid out on the board:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/images/raspberry_pi/raspberry_pi_model_b_schematic.png&quot; title=&quot;Raspberry Pi Model B Schematic&quot; alt=&quot;Raspberry Pi Model B Schematic&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Single-board systems like the Raspberry Pi aren&amp;#8217;t just miniaturized computers locked in a box, though. They&amp;#8217;re open, development boards with general inputs and outputs (GPIOs) that allow expansion through add-on boards and external devices. Installing a Linux distribution like Fedora is just the first step of becoming a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/geekmom/2012/10/open-hardware-summit-2012&quot;&gt;maker&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Who maintains the Fedora Remix for the Raspberry Pi?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It begins with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Architectures/ARM&quot;&gt;Fedora &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;ARM&lt;/span&gt; project&lt;/a&gt;, an initiative to port Fedora to the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;ARM&lt;/span&gt; processor family. The group has successfully created &lt;a href=&quot;http://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Architectures/ARM/Fedora_17_GA&quot;&gt;Fedora 17 GA images&lt;/a&gt; for single-board computers including the BeagleBoard, SheevaPlug, PandaBoard, and Trim-Slice. However, the Fedora Project does not yet produce an official release for the Raspberry Pi due to certain licensing issues. Specifically, the Raspberry Pi relies upon a custom kernel (not upstream) as well as special &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;GPU&lt;/span&gt; binary blobs which are not acceptable under the current firmware exception in Fedora.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, if you want Fedora 17 on your Pi &lt;strong&gt;today&lt;/strong&gt;, do not despair! There&amp;#8217;s a Fedora Remix for that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/images/raspberry_pi/raspberry_pi_fedora_remix_logo.png&quot; title=&quot;Raspberry Pi Fedora Remix Logo&quot; alt=&quot;Raspberry Pi Fedora Remix Logo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seneca College&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://zenit.senecac.on.ca/wiki/&quot;&gt;Centre for Development of Open Source Technology&lt;/a&gt; maintains the &lt;a href=&quot;http://zenit.senecac.on.ca/wiki/index.php/Raspberry_Pi_Fedora_Remix&quot;&gt;Raspberry Pi Fedora Remix&lt;/a&gt;. A &lt;a href=&quot;http://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Remix&quot;&gt;Fedora Remix&lt;/a&gt; is a combination of Fedora software, with or without add-ons, that any community member can create at any time to produce interesting and compelling distributions. The Raspberry Pi Fedora Remix enables you load Fedora 17 onto the Pi and get updates for most software from the official Fedora yum repositories (armv5tel architecture). &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RbWE6qF7pIM&quot;&gt;Watch the announcement video&lt;/a&gt; to learn more about how the folks from Sececa built and tested it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fedora &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;ARM&lt;/span&gt; group is working to make &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;ARM&lt;/span&gt; a primary Fedora architecture for all future releases and to expand support to additional SoCs, including the Raspberry Pi. Until Fedora officially supports the Raspberry Pi, you&amp;#8217;ll need to use the Fedora Remix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How do I get a Raspberry Pi and the Fedora Remix?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#8217;s take it one question at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do I get a Raspberry Pi?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may have heard that you need to know the right people to get your hands on a Raspberry Pi or that there is a purchasing restriction. Neither of those rumors are true anymore, though you may still run into backorders. Numerous distributors&lt;sup&gt;&amp;#8224;&lt;/sup&gt; sell the Pi, including &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alliedelec.com/lp/120626raso/?cm_mmc=Offline-Referral-_-Electronics-_-RaspberryPi-201203-_-World-Selector-Page&quot;&gt;Allied Electronics&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newark.com/jsp/search/productdetail.jsp?id=83T1943&amp;amp;Ntt=83T1943&quot;&gt;Newark&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.adafruit.com/category/105&quot;&gt;Adafruit Industries&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mcmelectronics.com/content/en-US/raspberry-pi&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;MCM&lt;/span&gt; Electronics&lt;/a&gt; but be prepared to wait (last minute holiday shoppers, you&amp;#8217;ve been warned!). &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;MCM&lt;/span&gt; Electronics and Adafruit also sell an array of accessories like the clear case that houses my Pi, shown below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/images/raspberry_pi/adafruit_case.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Adafruit Raspberry Pi Case&quot; alt=&quot;Adafruit Raspberry Pi Case&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do I load Fedora Remix on it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you receive your slice of Pi, the next step is to install Fedora Remix or one of the other &lt;a href=&quot;http://elinux.org/RPi_Distributions&quot;&gt;Raspberry Pi (RPi) Linux distributions&lt;/a&gt; onto a MicroSD card and slide it into the board. The next blog entry in this series will step through downloading Fedora Remix, installing it on your Pi and getting it up and running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Does the Raspberry Pi have a handbook?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to become more familiar with your Raspberry Pi and the story behind it, check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Raspberry-User-Guide-Gareth-Halfacree/dp/111846446X&quot;&gt;Raspberry Pi User Guide&lt;/a&gt;, written by the Pi&amp;#8217;s master chef. That&amp;#8217;s the book I read before booting the Raspberry Pi for the first time (on the plane heading to Ohio LinuxFest :)). Having that background knowledge helped make the installation process a breeze.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;muted&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&amp;#8224;&lt;/sup&gt; We&amp;#8217;re not endorsing any of the listed distributors of the Raspberry Pi or its accessories. The companies mentioned are just a sampling of results returned after executing a &amp;#8220;buy Raspberry Pi&amp;#8221; internet search. Sarah&amp;#8217;s Pi was gifted to her by a spotted hypnotoad. Dan purchased the Adafruit case through &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;MCM&lt;/span&gt; Electronics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;muted&quot;&gt;Raspberry Pi is a trademark of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://raspberrypi.org&quot;&gt;Raspberry Pi Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://graphitefriction.com/blog/2012/08/14/fedora-at-oscon-presented-with-a-raspberry-pi/</id>
    <title>Fedora at OSCON 2012, presented with a Raspberry Pi</title>
    <updated>2012-08-14T13:30:00Z</updated>
    <published>2012-08-14T13:30:00Z</published>
    <link href="http://graphitefriction.com/blog/2012/08/14/fedora-at-oscon-presented-with-a-raspberry-pi/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <author>
      <name>Sarah White</name>
    </author>
    <category scheme="http://graphitefriction.com/blog/tags" term="fedora" />
    <category scheme="http://graphitefriction.com/blog/tags" term="event" />
    <category scheme="http://graphitefriction.com/blog/tags" term="raspberry-pi" />
    <summary>
      At OSCON 2012 in Portland, OR the Fedora booth may have been small, but it packed a full cast of characters and crowd-gathering technology. Beefy Miracle waved from atop the Fedora marquee and Tux stopped by for a few hours each day. Few attendees could resist posing for a picture with Tux or snagging a Beefy Miracle sticker to embellish their laptop.
          
          
          Fedora on a Raspberry Pi
          The Fedora booth showcased the features and capabilities of Fedora running on a Raspberry Pi (a cheap, low-power computer that features an ARM processor). People were in awe that a tiny system on a chip...
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      &lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;At &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;OSCON&lt;/span&gt; 2012 in Portland, OR the Fedora booth may have been small, but it packed a full cast of characters and crowd-gathering technology. Beefy Miracle waved from atop the Fedora marquee and Tux stopped by for a few hours each day. Few attendees could resist posing for a picture with Tux or snagging a Beefy Miracle sticker to embellish their laptop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/images/oscon2012/deb_and_gunnar.png&quot; title=&quot;Deb and Gunnar at the Fedora booth&quot; alt=&quot;Deb and Gunnar at the Fedora booth&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/images/oscon2012/ruth_and_tux.png&quot; title=&quot;Ruth and Tux at the Fedora booth&quot; alt=&quot;Ruth and Tux at the Fedora booth&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fedora on a Raspberry Pi&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fedora booth showcased the features and capabilities of Fedora running on a Raspberry Pi (a cheap, low-power computer that features an &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;ARM&lt;/span&gt; processor). People were in awe that a tiny system on a chip (SoC) could support a widescreen monitor and an external hard drive and run full length movies at 1080p resolution with no problems (except when I overheated the chip by leaving my laptop next to it (my bad!)).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Common Raspberry Pi questions included:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
	&lt;dt&gt;Is that a Raspberry Pi?&lt;/dt&gt;
	&lt;dd&gt;Yes&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
	&lt;dt&gt;What operating system is it running?&lt;/dt&gt;
	&lt;dd&gt;Raspberry Pi Fedora Remix (armv5hl), maintained by the Fedora &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;ARM&lt;/span&gt; team&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
	&lt;dt&gt;What is the desktop?&lt;/dt&gt;
	&lt;dd&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;XFCE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
	&lt;dt&gt;What is the graphics card brand?&lt;/dt&gt;
	&lt;dd&gt;A Broadcom VideoCore IV, OpenGL ES 2.0, that is capable of 1080p, 30 h.264/&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;MPEG&lt;/span&gt;-4 &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;AVC&lt;/span&gt; high-profile decoder. The output connections are Composite &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;RCA&lt;/span&gt; or &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;HDMI&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
	&lt;dt&gt;Does it have on board memory?&lt;/dt&gt;
	&lt;dd&gt;No. You have to boot from SD but a &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;USB&lt;/span&gt; HD can &amp;#8220;take over&amp;#8221; after the initial boot. You cannot boot without an SD card. Supported card formats include SD, &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;MMC&lt;/span&gt;, and &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;SDIO&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
	&lt;dt&gt;How is it powered?&lt;/dt&gt;
	&lt;dd&gt;The device is powered by 5V micro &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;USB&lt;/span&gt;. The device could also be run by 4 AA batteries.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
	&lt;dt&gt;Can it display at 1080?&lt;/dt&gt;
	&lt;dd&gt;Yes&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our setup used an external hard drive connected via &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;USB&lt;/span&gt; because the SD card was only large enough to fit Futurama episodes (in 720), not the full length Tron Legacy movie Spot had on hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information about the Raspberry Pi hardware, refer to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/http://www.raspberrypi.org/faqs&quot;&gt;Raspberry Pi Foundation&amp;#8217;s FAQs&lt;/a&gt;. Visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Architectures/ARM&quot;&gt;Fedora &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;ARM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to learn more about how Fedora is developing architectures for SoC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tux Photobooth&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Raspberry Pi ran the semi-automated photography booth. Hooked up to a camera and using a python script, the Pi snapped photos of the attendees posed with Tux. Attendees could then scan the QR code generated by the script and displayed in the web browser to retrieve their picture later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/images/oscon2012/fedora_photo_booth.png&quot; title=&quot;Fedora photobooth&quot; alt=&quot;Fedora photobooth&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first photobooth session occurred on Tuesday night, during the opening of the expo floor. During the ever-popular &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;OSCON&lt;/span&gt; booth crawl on Wednesday night, Tux returned to the photobooth and later toured the expo floor to meet his fans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amazing fact:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Tux can write python code with his wings!&lt;/em&gt; Prior to the session on Wednesday, Tux took a few moments to modify the python program that captures, scales, and posts the pictures when the usual Nikon was replaced with a Canon (new drivers had to be loaded). The equipment and instructions to host your own Raspberry Pi photobooth are being drafted on the new &lt;a href=&quot;http://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Raspberry_Pi_photobooth&quot;&gt;Raspberry Pi photobooth wikipage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/images/oscon2012/tux_tour.png&quot; title=&quot;Tux touring the OSCON Expo floor&quot; alt=&quot;Tux touring the OSCON Expo floor&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fedora Packages Search App&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did field a few questions about Fedora 17&amp;#8217;s development environment and got to point out the servers and frameworks packaged in Fedora 17. There was also a question about the latest &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;KVM&lt;/span&gt; virt-manager instance. I&amp;#8217;m just learning about virtual machine technologies, and version numbers are not my strong point. However, this allowed me to show off the &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.fedoraproject.org/packages/virt-manager&quot;&gt;Fedora Packages Search&lt;/a&gt; app (using Firefox on the Pi!). If you&amp;#8217;re not familiar with the Fedora packages search app, you need to check it out. It rocks!  You can quickly find out if the program you&amp;#8217;re interested in is packaged, which version is packaged in which release, what updates are coming, and much more all within a clean, easy to use web interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use the packages search app almost every day as I continue to learn more about Fedora&amp;#8217;s features, release cycle, and the awesome people dedicated to adding new and improved programs and capabilities to Fedora.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Photographs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find more pictures from &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;OSCON&lt;/span&gt; 2012 on my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/graphitefriction/sets/72157630714547678/&quot;&gt;photostream&lt;/a&gt;. Mark Terranova (MarkDude) also took great photographs of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/u/0/photos/105095769731159704550/albums/5769140764406115713&quot;&gt;Fedora booth and Beefy Miracle&amp;#8217;s expo floor adventures&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;OSCON&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who stopped by the booth!&lt;/p&gt;
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://graphitefriction.com/blog/2012/08/03/fedora-contributors-will-show-off-their-bash-and-gluster-at-txlf-this-weekend/</id>
    <title>Fedora contributors will show off their BASH and GLUSTER at TXLF this weekend</title>
    <updated>2012-08-03T13:30:00Z</updated>
    <published>2012-08-03T13:30:00Z</published>
    <link href="http://graphitefriction.com/blog/2012/08/03/fedora-contributors-will-show-off-their-bash-and-gluster-at-txlf-this-weekend/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <author>
      <name>Sarah White</name>
    </author>
    <category scheme="http://graphitefriction.com/blog/tags" term="fedora" />
    <category scheme="http://graphitefriction.com/blog/tags" term="event" />
    <summary>
      Fedora contributors John Rose and Thomas Cameron will be speaking in San Antonio this Saturday at the Texas Linux Fest.
          John Rose (inode0), a current Fedora Board member and the North American Fedora Ambassador leader, will explain how to rid your shell scripts of useless cats.
          
          
          Demoggification
          Saturday August 4, 2012 2:25 PM &#8211; 3:10 PM
          Since the mid 1990s the Useless Use of Cat Award has raised awareness of a class of shell script constructs that make some laugh and others cry. Demoggification is the process of removing useless cats. This talk covers a variety of other useless stuff (including echo, grep, sed,...
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      &lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;Fedora contributors John Rose and Thomas Cameron will be speaking in San Antonio this Saturday at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://2012.texaslinuxfest.org/&quot;&gt;Texas Linux Fest&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;John Rose (&lt;a href=&quot;http://fedoraproject.org/wiki/User:Inode0&quot;&gt;inode0&lt;/a&gt;), a current Fedora Board member and the North American &lt;a href=&quot;http://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Ambassadors&quot;&gt;Fedora Ambassador&lt;/a&gt; leader, will explain how to rid your shell scripts of useless cats.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;citation&quot;&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/images/TXLF_Badge_transparent_175.png&quot; class=&quot;pull-left&quot; title=&quot;Texas Linux Fest 2012&quot; alt=&quot;Texas Linux Fest 2012&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2012.texaslinuxfest.org/sessions/demoggification&quot;&gt;Demoggification&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
          &lt;p class=&quot;byline&quot;&gt;Saturday August 4, 2012 2:25 PM &amp;#8211; 3:10 PM&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;Since the mid 1990s the Useless Use of Cat Award has raised awareness of a class of shell script constructs that make some laugh and others cry. Demoggification is the process of removing useless cats. This talk covers a variety of other useless stuff (including echo, grep, sed, nc, and more) that frequently finds its way into our shell scripts and shows how to demoggify each by using various features in bash.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;Features covered include direct access to sockets, parameter expansions, brace expansions, here strings, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;Thomas Cameron (&lt;a href=&quot;http://fedoraproject.org/wiki/User:Tcameron&quot;&gt;Tcameron&lt;/a&gt;), Red Hat&amp;#8217;s chief architect for Canada and the central US, will show how scaling out with software based on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gluster.org/&quot;&gt;Gluster&lt;/a&gt; will defy future data storage and transfer resource constraints.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;citation&quot;&gt;
          &lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2012.texaslinuxfest.org/sessions/building-software-based-nas-using-gluster-red-hat-storage-software-appliance&quot;&gt;Building Software-Based &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;NAS&lt;/span&gt; Using Gluster&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
          &lt;p class=&quot;byline&quot;&gt;Saturday August 4, 2012 3:20 PM &amp;#8211; 4:05 PM&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;Gluster is a software-based, scale-out network-attached storage (&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;NAS&lt;/span&gt;) appliance. It uses inexpensive internal or direct-attached (e.g. &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;JBOD&lt;/span&gt;) storage and pools multiple servers into one storage namespace. This pooled storage is then exported to Linux clients via &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;NFS&lt;/span&gt;, to Microsoft Windows clients via &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;CIFS&lt;/span&gt;/Samba, or using the native Gluster client. In this session, Red Hat&amp;#8217;s Thomas Cameron will explain the architecture of Gluster and demonstrate setting up a 3-node storage cluster, including setting up the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;NFS&lt;/span&gt; service, Samba, and the native Gluster client. He will demonstrate mirrored content, distributed content, and discuss geo-replication (stretch clusters).&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/images/beefybutton_300.png&quot; class=&quot;pull-right&quot; title=&quot;Beefy Miracle Fedora 17&quot; alt=&quot;Beefy Miracle Fedora 17&quot; /&gt; Also make sure to stop by the Fedora booth on the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;TXLF&lt;/span&gt; Expo floor and grab a Beefy Miracle button or sticker. More information about the Fedora booth and activities at &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;TXFL&lt;/span&gt; is located on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://fedoraproject.org/wiki/TXLF_2012&quot;&gt;Fedora event page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://graphitefriction.com/blog/2012/07/05/chronicling-the-fedora-community-area-in-millimeters-and-pixels/</id>
    <title>Chronicling the Fedora Community Area in Millimeters and Pixels</title>
    <updated>2012-07-05T13:30:00Z</updated>
    <published>2012-07-05T13:30:00Z</published>
    <link href="http://graphitefriction.com/blog/2012/07/05/chronicling-the-fedora-community-area-in-millimeters-and-pixels/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <author>
      <name>Sarah White</name>
    </author>
    <category scheme="http://graphitefriction.com/blog/tags" term="fedora" />
    <category scheme="http://graphitefriction.com/blog/tags" term="event" />
    <summary>
      Representing Fedora at the Summit sounded great when I was safely ensconced in my office, chatting on IRC, weeks before the event.  But once I approached the booth at the Hynes Convention Center, a horde of heebie-jeebies streaked down my spine screaming, Run away! Run away!.
Face to face, live action conversation? It can&#8217;t be paused, reconsidered or erased. Answering direct questions without the luxury of composing my thoughts on paper? Why, oh why hasn&#8217;t anyone invented a delete key for my mouth!
During the first full day of booth activities, I retreated behind my cameras to document the constant activity...
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      &lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;Representing &lt;a href=&quot;http://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Red_Hat_Summit_2012&quot;&gt;Fedora at the Summit&lt;/a&gt; sounded great when I was safely ensconced in my office, chatting on &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;IRC&lt;/span&gt;, weeks before the event.  But once I approached the booth at the Hynes Convention Center, a horde of heebie-jeebies streaked down my spine screaming, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Run away! Run away!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Face to face, live action conversation? It can&amp;#8217;t be paused, reconsidered or erased. Answering direct questions without the luxury of composing my thoughts on paper? Why, oh why hasn&amp;#8217;t anyone invented a delete key for my mouth!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the first full day of booth activities, I retreated behind my cameras to document the constant activity in the Fedora Community area. I photographed attendees visiting the Fedora booth, hanging with Beefy Miracle, and enjoying the mid-afternoon hot dog snack hour. All of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/graphitefriction/&quot;&gt;photographs I took during the Summit&lt;/a&gt; are posted on my Flickr stream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/images/fedorasummit2012/fedora_booth_friends.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/images/fedorasummit2012/beefymiracle_mustard.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also recorded two talks presented in the Fedora Community area: Ryan O&amp;#8217;Hara&amp;#8217;s &lt;em&gt;Network Load Balancing for the 21st Century With Keepalived and HAProxy&lt;/em&gt; and Dan Allen&amp;#8217;s &lt;em&gt;JBoss AS7 on Fedora&lt;/em&gt; as well as the server and system installation for the next day&amp;#8217;s Fedora &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;ARM&lt;/span&gt; demonstration. Once I finish processing the videos, I&amp;#8217;ll post them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/images/fedorasummit2012/ryanohara_loadbalance.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Ryan O&amp;#39;Hara&quot; alt=&quot;Ryan O&amp;#39;Hara&quot; /&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/images/fedorasummit2012/danallen_as7onfedora.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Dan Allen&quot; alt=&quot;Dan Allen&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/images/fedorasummit2012/jonmasters_arm_demo.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Jon Masters&quot; alt=&quot;Jon Masters&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, after Jon Masters&amp;#8217; crowd-gathering &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;ARM&lt;/span&gt; demonstration, I forced myself to stow the cameras. I took position behind the booth, no camera lenses or laptop to filter my I/O. The gaps in my knowledge soon became apparent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left:2em;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No, I&amp;#8217;m not familiar with the wide variety of acronyms applied to the hardware in the one laptop per per child computer or what version of Fedora it is running.&lt;/strong&gt; Luke Macken saved the attendee from my panicky stare, and now I know it&amp;#8217;s an &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;ARM&lt;/span&gt; processor, running Sugar on a Stick, and the newest laptop has a much better keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left:2em;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t know what version of Apache httpd is packaged in Fedora 17.&lt;/strong&gt; Tom Callaway fired up a terminal and found the information. &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.fedoraproject.org/packages/httpd&quot;&gt;2.2.22&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the most popular question at the booth:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left:2em;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How did Beefy Miracle come to be named Beefy Miracle?&lt;/strong&gt; After numerous attempts, I realized I couldn&amp;#8217;t succinctly explain the &lt;a href=&quot;http://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Guidelines_for_release_names&quot;&gt;Fedora release naming process steps&lt;/a&gt; in the correct order. Ruth Suehle, Sandro Mathys and Tom had to save people from my disordered explanations numerous times. They can iterate the naming process without blinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I did answer questions regarding one of the new items at the booth, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://fedoraproject.org/wiki/JBossAS7&quot;&gt;AS 7 on Fedora 17&lt;/a&gt; flyer.  I can recite the commands to install the AS 7 package, start, stop and deploy it, what is and isn&amp;#8217;t currently in the packaged profile, what&amp;#8217;s on deck to be in updated releases, and where to find help and participate with AS 7 and future packaging goals.  I was stumped though when asked about the differences between Fedora and AS 7 versus another distribution and Websphere.  I need to brush up on the features of other application servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m not a well-rounded Fedora representative yet, but manning the booth was a huge kickstart. I learned the answers to tons of questions from the other Fedora representatives and discovered the concerns of potential and current Fedora users. The best thing about volunteering at the booth was meeting so many great people: the conference attendees who visited the booth and the Fedora advocates I had previously only chatted with on &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;IRC&lt;/span&gt;. I can&amp;#8217;t thank everyone enough times for answering my questions or for sorting through my jumbled explanations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, there are two questions I can confidently respond to now without pause or consideration because Ruth wrote down the answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yes, it is a Raspberry Pi. No, you can&amp;#8217;t have it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/images/fedorasummit2012/raspberrypi_fedora17.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you&amp;#8217;d like a specific picture from the Fedora booth in its high-resolution, mega-size version (some are available in large format &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;JPG&lt;/span&gt; and some in &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;RAW&lt;/span&gt;), just shoot me a message. I&amp;#8217;m graphite6 in the Fedora &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;IRC&lt;/span&gt; channels.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://graphitefriction.com/blog/2012/06/16/molecules-and-predators-and-arquillian/</id>
    <title>Molecules and Predators and Arquillian</title>
    <updated>2012-06-16T13:30:00Z</updated>
    <published>2012-06-16T13:30:00Z</published>
    <link href="http://graphitefriction.com/blog/2012/06/16/molecules-and-predators-and-arquillian/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <author>
      <name>Sarah White</name>
    </author>
    <category scheme="http://graphitefriction.com/blog/tags" term="arquillian" />
    <category scheme="http://graphitefriction.com/blog/tags" term="design" />
    <summary>
      During the past year Arquillian has matured from a testing harness to a testing platform as it integrates with Selenium, Graphene, Spring, Android and more. In parallel, the Arquillian contributors have channeled their interlanguage and interframework development exploits into an ongoing tale of intergalactic bug extermination. Ike is gathering a crew as he expands into new frontiers. He&#8217;s using new tools to hunt for bugs and congifuring weapons with super strong materials to eliminate the bugs.
              Crafting the look and feel of Ike, his crew, and their gear has this sci-fi fangirl constantly plotting ways to beam (forgive me, Scotty) the...
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      &lt;p class=&quot;lead&quot;&gt;During the past year &lt;a href=&quot;http://arquillian.org/&quot;&gt;Arquillian&lt;/a&gt; has matured from a testing harness to a testing platform as it integrates with Selenium, Graphene, Spring, Android and more. In parallel, the Arquillian contributors have channeled their interlanguage and interframework development exploits into an ongoing tale of intergalactic bug extermination. Ike is gathering a crew as he expands into new frontiers. He&amp;#8217;s using new tools to hunt for bugs and congifuring weapons with super strong materials to eliminate the bugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crafting the look and feel of Ike, his crew, and their gear has this sci-fi fangirl constantly plotting ways to beam (forgive me, Scotty) the Arquillian platform artwork to the next dimension. However, the platform has diversified so rapidly that I can&amp;#8217;t pull off diagrams, icons, and logos during all-night design binges hours before a presentation deadline. Nor does such a draw-and-dash design frenzy do the indvidual extensions, adaptors, and modules the creative and finely polished rendering justice they deserve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m also a bit of a monster after thirty-six hours of no sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, Arquillian now has a &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/arquillian/arquillian-artwork&quot;&gt;seperate repository&lt;/a&gt; where graphics can be conceptualized, drafted, and finalized over multiple iterations. It&amp;#8217;s powered by community requests, community contributions, and community feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Initial logo concepts: Graphene and Arquillian Spring Framework extension&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past two weeks I&amp;#8217;ve been sketching logo ideas for Graphene and the Arquillian Spring Framework extension.  I selected the sketches I think have potential and uploaded them for the feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://arquillian.org/modules/graphene-extension/&quot;&gt;Graphene&lt;/a&gt; is designed to enhancement a Selenium project by focusing on rapid development and usability in the Java environment.  Graphene takes its name from the semiconducting material composed of a single layer of carbon atoms arranged into a 2D honeycomb lattice. Graphene is one of the strongest materials in existence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to admit, I don&amp;#8217;t feel that pencil sketches were great at coveying some of my ideas. Mainly because I realized I really suck at drawing hexagrams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/images/graphene/graphenehexagrams.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/images/graphene/abstracthexagram.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/images/graphene/grapheneshield.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next three concepts required lots of hexagrams, so I stopped torturing my eraser and fired up Inkscape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/images/graphene/grid1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/images/graphene/grid2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/images/graphene/grid3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://arquillian.org/modules/spring-extension/&quot;&gt;Spring extension&lt;/a&gt; is &lt;a href=&quot;https://community.jboss.org/thread/197356&quot;&gt;Jakob Narloch&amp;#8217;s Google Summer of Code project&lt;/a&gt;. It injects Spring beans into test cases and supports Spring annotations. Jakob asked for a simple logo, but my disciple went &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;AWOL&lt;/span&gt; and I ended up sketching a few, detailed ideas after word webbing like the vocabulary nerd I am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/images/spring/springs.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/images/spring/bow.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/images/spring/viper.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/images/spring/foxspring.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://graphitefriction.com/images/spring/mutanttrap.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>http://graphitefriction.com/blog/2012/06/15/fatal-error-problematic-frame-there-goes-my-core/</id>
    <title>A Fatal Error. A Problematic Frame. There Goes My Core.</title>
    <updated>2012-06-15T13:30:00Z</updated>
    <published>2012-06-15T13:30:00Z</published>
    <link href="http://graphitefriction.com/blog/2012/06/15/fatal-error-problematic-frame-there-goes-my-core/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <author>
      <name>Sarah White</name>
    </author>
    <category scheme="http://graphitefriction.com/blog/tags" term="java" />
    <category scheme="http://graphitefriction.com/blog/tags" term="ruby" />
    <category scheme="http://graphitefriction.com/blog/tags" term="smack" />
    <summary>
      A fatal error has been detected by the Java Runtime Environment:
SIGSEGV (0xb) at pc=0x00007f995359f24d, pid=4003, tid=140296504968960
Translation for mere humans: It&#8217;s dead, Sarah. You killed something important-sounding by attempting to build a teeny, tiny little webpage on localhost. Sigh.
Java VM: OpenJDK 64-Bit Server VM (22.0-b10 mixed mode linux-amd64 compressed oops)
Is this an oops my laptop accidentally mixed up some important bits? Or OOPS the official operations processing specialists ARE FROWNING UPON my coding attempts?
Problematic frame:
C  [libjruby-cext.so+0x2624d] Java_org_jruby_cext_Native_freeHandle+0xb7
Oh, so now it&#8217;s just &#8216;problematic&#8217; not FATAL. Make up your mind already!
Failed to write core dump. Core dumps have been disabled. To enable...
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;A fatal error has been detected by the Java Runtime Environment:&amp;#x000A;SIGSEGV (0xb) at pc=0x00007f995359f24d, pid=4003, tid=140296504968960&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Translation for mere humans: It&amp;#8217;s dead, Sarah. You killed something important-sounding by attempting to build a teeny, tiny little webpage on localhost. &lt;em&gt;Sigh.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Java VM: OpenJDK 64-Bit Server VM (22.0-b10 mixed mode linux-amd64 compressed oops)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this an &lt;em&gt;oops&lt;/em&gt; my laptop accidentally mixed up some important bits? Or &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;OOPS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; the official operations processing specialists &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;ARE&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;FROWNING&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;UPON&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; my coding attempts?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Problematic frame:&amp;#x000A;C  [libjruby-cext.so+0x2624d] Java_org_jruby_cext_Native_freeHandle+0xb7&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, so now it&amp;#8217;s just &amp;#8216;problematic&amp;#8217; not &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;FATAL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Make up your mind already!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Failed to write core dump. Core dumps have been disabled. To enable core dumping, try &quot;ulimit -c unlimited&quot; before starting Java again.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Core dumps sound bad. They&amp;#8217;re always the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;LAST&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;RESORT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in movies.  If we detach the rest of the train cars maybe we&amp;#8217;ll make the leap across the giant canyon. If we shoot our nuclear reactor out a torpedo tube maybe we&amp;#8217;ll kill the bad guys chasing us (but obliterate all life in the Pacific ocean).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Aborted (core dumped)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The heck with the stupid core anyway. Where&amp;#8217;s my dilithium crystal virtual machine? Then I could sling shot my laptop around the sun before the terminal would even dare to mention errors to me. Of course, then my laptop would probably learn to cloak itself as well and hide from me.  My laptop might not be able to pass the Turing test but I betcha it could score major points on the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;DSM&lt;/span&gt;-IV antisocial personality test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I don&amp;#8217;t want to hear anything about how one&amp;#8217;s computer is a reflection of its user.&lt;/p&gt;
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
